JORDAN "JJ" CARDENAS

Woodinville, WA

Phone: 425-922-3350 | Email: jj@jjcardenas.com

 $\textbf{LinkedIn:} \ linkedin.com/in/jordanj cardenas \ | \ \textbf{GitHub:} \ github.com/cardeens$

Portfolio: www.jjcardenas.com

SUMMARY

Recent graduate of an intensive full stack development program backed by five years as a marketing professional in the technology industry. Dedicated, personable, fast learner seeking an entry-level frontend developer role where I can combine my marketing knowledge with my new-found technical skills to help reach millions by building the next great experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: ReactJS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Java, Node.js, Bootstrap, Material-UI,

Handlebars.js, Express, MERN Stack **Databases:** MySQL, MongoDB

Deployment & Version Control: Git, Heroku, GoDaddy

PROJECTS

Quiz Panda | https://github.com/sali6798/quiz-panda | https://quizpanda.herokuapp.com/

Simple and responsive application that allows users to create surveys and quizzes and share them with friends via email to see who can get the highest score

- Participated with a team of four in all phases of the development life cycle, focusing on coding, testing, and debugging
- Completed the application in less than one week collaborating remotely using Zoom and Slack and presented to class & instructors
- Front end developer: brainstormed the overall the user experience and built out the front-end code with Handlebars, JavaScript, HTML, and Foundation CSS package
- Awards: Best App Overall, Best UI

MGR | https://github.com/sali6798/mgr-react | https://mgr-talent.herokuapp.com/

Marketing automation tool targeted to the music industry to help record label staff manage social media efforts for their artists

- Two-week team project with agile approach and remote SCRUM meetings
- Front end developer: built out front end experience with React and Material-UI
- Implemented Node packages such as Nodemailer, Express, BCrypt, Uniqid doteny, and Cron
- Thoroughly documented all code changes through a front-end and back-end repository in GitHub to follow versioning best practices
- Awards: Best UI

Google Books | github.com/cardeens/googlebooks | jj-googlebooksfinal.herokuapp.com

Responsive application that uses the Google Books API to search for books and allows users to save or remove titles from their Saved list

- Built individually using MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js) and routed search queries from Google Books API
- Thorough testing, troubleshooting, and debugging across front and back end code to create functional and responsive application
- Deployed final application through Heroku and have continued to push continuous improvements

FINDR | https://github.com/commiewalker/Findr | https://cardeens.github.io/FindrApp/index.html Simple and user-friendly application that randomly displays an image from a restaurant in a card that can be cycled through until an appealing option is picked. Once the top choice is chosen, the restaurant information will be shown to get a user to their food as fast as possible

- Initially worked in a team of four in a one-week period to develop, debug, and deploy application
 using the Zomato and Google Maps APIs on the back end and Bootstrap to format the front end
- After the program, individually took initiative and updated the app to use Yelp Fusion API in an effort to continuously improve the app and provide the best possible user experience

EXPERIENCE

Marketing Strategy Consultant
Lenati LLC

July 2019 – March 2020
Seattle, WA

Worked independently across key account such as Microsoft, T-Mobile, and Vans to drive several successful, high-visibility marketing and program management projects *Key Accomplishments:*

- Led content reviews for Microsoft Ignite presentations with engineering and product subject matter experts and ultimately achieved the highest satisfaction rating across business groups
- Set and surpassed target goal of Pluralsight training modules pushed to production while acting
 as a project manager and successfully eliminating roadblocks, presenting progress to managers,
 and identifying technical and business requirements

Sr. Marketing Specialist March 2016 – July 2019

Xevo Inc. Bellevue, WA

Collaborated cross-functionally in a fast-faced, ambiguous startup environment to support and lead marketing programs and product development efforts Key Accomplishments:

- Demonstrated ability to learn quickly, work both independently and in teams, and analyze data to deliver on client requests and meet deadlines for co-marketing activities
- Applied critical thinking and worked with UX team to research best possible user experience for new cutting-edge applications that aligned with business requirements
- Worked with senior leadership to rebrand company and build out new web, print, and video content to support the company's new vision and brand

Account Executive July 2015 – February 2016

Digital Intelligence Systems Kirkland, WA

Eagerly took on key ownership to manage accounts within the high-tech industry vertical, namely Microsoft and Facebook

Key Accomplishments:

 Proactively built trusting and personable relationships with hiring managers at client sites by building an understanding of team needs and setting goals for client success

VOLUNTEER

Social Media Strategist July 2016 – March 2019

HERE Seattle Seattle, WA

Led marketing programs and community engagement efforts on the leadership team for a non-profit dedicated to supporting an inclusive culture in technology and making a positive impact in the Seattle community

EDUCATION

Full Stack Development Certificate: University of Washington, Seattle, WA May 2020

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

BA in Business Administration, Marketing Major: Seattle University, Seattle, WA

Dean's List for Albers School of Business and Economics (Fall 2013-Spring 2015)